Guide to the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Information about Adele Nathan's friends and family is found in additional clippings and documents. The clippings subsection contains profiles of many of Nathan's acquaintances (Box 19, folder 621). The Gutman Family subsection chronicles several generations of Nathan's family through a variety of documents. Additionally, Box 19, folders 637-41, provide information on Joel Gutman & Co., the Baltimore department store founded by Nathan's grandfather.
The largest section within Series IV is a collection of printed materials which came with the archives. Many items herein concern theatrical issues, including copies of magazines such as The Festival Theatre Review, Theatre Arts, and Theatre Arts Monthly. Several playbills from the 1920s-40s are also filed here (Box 21, folders 697-98). Besides materials from Goucher College, other ephemera include a copy of The Irish World and American Industrial Liberator from 1926, and a single copy of The Masses from 1917.
Two scrapbooks containing a wide range of information on many of Adele Nathan's activities are found in the Personal Papers series. Scrapbook 1, disbound and foldered in Box 22, folders 718-36 includes clippings and documents about the following subjects in approximate page order: Cellar Players, Vagabond Players, The Iron Horse, Lenox Hill Players, Vogue magazine articles, Baltimore & Ohio Railroad Pageant Centenary Pageant, Baltimore Hebrew Congregation Centennial, Rochester Pageant of Progress, L. Bamberger & Co., "Famous Folk" Radio Interview (1930), Museum of the City of New York, Syrian Junior League, and the Town Club Players. Scrapbook 2, housed in Oversize (Box 28, folder 859), contains clippings on the following matters: Forsythorama, and the Independence Savings Bond Campaign.
The final folder in this series yields some of the only information extant in the archives about Nathan's husband, James Nathan. A parody wedding newspaper, The Daily N.G. Tornado, includes jokes and poems about the couple on their wedding day, February 20, 1912.
Series V, Photographs, consists of snapshots and photographic portraits taken principally during the early and late days of Adele Nathan's life. The Gutman family is portrayed between 1850 and 1930 in six albums containing albumen portraits and gelatin print snapshots. Housed in Oversize (Boxes 29 and 30), these photographs show Adele at various ages, from birth to approximately age 25, at school, on excursions with friends, with Etta Cone, and playing tennis. Album 3 concentrates more on her sister, Elizabeth Gutman Kaye. Loose photographs from this same period are housed under specific subjects in Boxes 23 and 24. Later photographs include informal shots of Adele with friends (Box 23, folder 758), and Adele at the Golden Spike Centennial in 1969 (Box 23, folder 760). Photographs relating specifically to, or documenting a particular pageant, stage production or other activities, such as awards presentations, are filed with other documents under the specific subject in the appropriate series.
The final series, Elizabeth Gutman Kaye Papers (Boxes 25-26), contains the documentary effects of Nathan's sister. This series mirrors the collection as a whole, consisting of many identical subseries. Biographical information about Elizabeth Kaye can be found in many of the clippings folders, specifically in Box 25, folders 793-96 and in the first folder of the Personal Papers section, Biographical sketches, Box 23, folder 813. The Correspondence section includes letters from the composer, Vincent D'Indy. Advertisements and publicity materials for Kaye's painting exhibitions and singing performances are found in Box 23, folders 806-07 and folders 810-12. The photographs included here are travel pictures belonging to Kaye. Portraits of Elizabeth Kaye, of her as a child with her family, and of her husband, Walter Kaye, are filed in Series V, Photographs.
Kaye's other creative works can be seen in the final sections of this series. Several scripts for radio programs on art history, such as Adventures in Art, are extant in the collection. Her writings include several printed columns concerning art exhibitions around Europe principally in the 1940s and 1950s, as well as her published book of poems, Patches of Light, and several individual poems. Kaye's venture into writing children's books survives in her manuscripts for The Magic Pussycat and Susie's Big Day, which is complete with watercolor illustrations.
Reds (Motion picture); Children's literature, American -- History and criticism; Community theater; Documentary films -- Production and direction; Jews -- Maryland -- Maryland -- Baltimore -- History; Jews -- United States -- Centennial celebrations, etc.; Little theater movement; Motion picture authorship; Pageants -- United States -- History -- 20th Century; Radio authorship; Theater -- Production and direction; Young adult literature -- History and criticism; Baltimore (Md.) -- History; Rochester (N.Y.) -- Centennial celebrations, etc.; Journalists -- United States; Allvine, Glendon; Colum, Padraic, 1881-1972; Cone, Claribel, 1864-1929; Cone, Etta, 1870-1949 -- Art collections; Cone, Etta, 1870-1949; Davis, Blevins; Diamant, Anita, 1951-; Gutman, Ida Newberger; Gutman, Louis K.; Hurst, Fannie, 1889-1968; Indy, Vincent d', 1851-1931; Joseph, Nannine; Kaye, Elizabeth Gutman, 1891-1971; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 -- Juvenile literature -- History and criticism; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956; Nathan, Adele Gutman; Newberger family; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 ( Comedy of A midsummer night's dream); Cellar Players (New York, N. Y.); Goucher College; Joel Gutman & Co. (Baltimore, Md.); L. Bamberger and Co. (New York, N. Y.); Little Lyric Theatre (Baltimore, Md.); Overseas Press Club of America; Vagabond Players (Baltimore, Md.); Weirton Steel Co. (Weirton, W. Va.); Woman Pays Club (New York, N. Y.); Gutmann family
- Writings, 1834-1985; Series I; 5.25; (13 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Writings, is subdivided into nine alphabetically arranged subseries.
  - BOOKS
    - Churchill's England
      - Advertisement, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Catalog notice, 1975
      - Clipping, 1964 May 23
      - Publication announcement, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Post-publication correspondence, 1963, n.d.
    - The Farmer Sows His Wheat
      - Publishing contract, 1932 Mar 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Clippings, 1932
      - Advertisement, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Father Marquette
      - Publishing contract, 1951 Mar 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Research Materials
        - Correspondence, 1951 Jun 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Illinois Catholic Historical Review, 1925 Jan (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Library call slips, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Notes, n.d.
        - "Narrative script of Pere Marquette Pageant", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Printed material, 1934-38, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Radio program script, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Chapter outlines, 1951, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Early chapter draft - Chapter 1, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Draft 1
        - typescript, corrected, [1951] (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - typescript, carbon, corrected, [1951] (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Draft 2
        - typescript, carbon, [1951] (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Draft 3
        - typescript, carbon, corrected, [1951] (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - The First Transatlantic Cable
      - Publishing contract, 1955 Jan 10 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Research material
        - Bell Telephone magazine, 1954-58 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Clippings, 1955, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Correspondence, 1951-55 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Library sources card file, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - Long Lines manuscript, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Pirelli magazine, 1957 Apr (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Telephone pamphlets, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Chapter outlines, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Book synopsis, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Early chapter drafts, 1955, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30-32)
      - Final draft, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
      - Post-publication correspondence, 1971 Mar 4 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Clippings, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Publicity photographs (with letter), n.d.
      - Post-publication clippings on related subjects, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Enrichment Landmark Records version
        - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - Script, 1961
        - Press release, 1961
    - How to Plan and Conduct a Bicentennial Celebration
      - Draft page, 1975 Jun 6 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Advertisement, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Clippings, 1972-75
      - Post-publication, 1975 Apr 17
    - Let's Play Garden
      - Contract, 1939 Aug 29 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Lincoln's America
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Fan mail, 1962-63
    - Major John André
      - Bibliographies of source material, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Clippings, 1965-75, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Printed material, 1953
      - Research notes, 1965-66, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Research queries and responses, 1965-66 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Manuscript notes, 1966, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Editorial notes, 1967, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Publisher's correspondence, 1967-69 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Sketches of minor characters, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Chapter outlines, 1965, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Early chapter drafts, typescript, corrected, 1965-67, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 52-72)
      - Draft 1, typescript, corrected, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 73-74)
      - Draft 2, typescript, corrected, [1966] (Box 3, Folder 75-79)
      - Draft 3, typescript, corrected, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 80-85)
      - Draft 3, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 86-91)
      - Draft 4, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 92-93)
      - Draft 4, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 94-95)
      - Later chapter drafts, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1968, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96-98)
      - Publication announcements, 1965-70 (Box 4, Folder 99)
      - Author biographical sketch, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 100)
      - Clippings, 1969-72 (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - Post-publication correspondence, 1969-75, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - Reprint ideas, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Seven Brave Companions
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Box 1, folders 12-18.
      - Clippings, 1953-54 (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - Post-publication correspondence, 1954 Feb 18
    - Victorian in Bohemia
      Research material
      - Cards, 1974, n.d.
      - Clippings
        See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 852
      - Correspondence, 1959, 1976, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - Historic Preservation, 1984 Oct (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1949-85, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - Notes, n.d.
      - Photographs, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 109)
      - Postcards, n.d.
      - Book proposal, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 110)
      - Dates outline, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - Book outlines, 1962 Jun (Box 4, Folder 112)
      - Chapter drafts, typescript, corrected
        - [Adele's trip to Paris], 1973 (Box 4, Folder 113)
        - [Aunt Etta], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 114)
        - [The Cones and the Gutmans], 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 115)
        - Death of Etta Cone, 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 116)
        - [Miss Bertha], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 117)
        - My Education, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - What is a Man Profited?
      - Editorial correspondence, 1953 Apr (Box 4, Folder 119)
      - Novel outline, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - Early chapter drafts, typescript, corrected
        - Front matter, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 121)
        - Steam, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 122-25)
        - Steel, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 126)
        - Smoke, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 127)
        - Cinders (Box 5, Folder 128)
        - Slag, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 129)
        - Salvage, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 130)
      - Draft 1, typescript, carbon, corrected
        - Steam, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 131-33)
        - Steel, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 134-35)
        - Slag, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 136-37)
      - Draft 2, typescript, corrected
        - Steam, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 138-39)
        - Steel, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 140)
        - Salvage, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 141)
      - Draft 2, typescript, carbon, corrected
        - Steam, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 142-43)
        - Steel, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 144)
        - Salvage, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 145)
      - Miscellaneous manuscript pages, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Wheat Won't Wait
      - Book outline, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 147)
      - Publisher's correspondence, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 148)
      - Research material
        - Caterpillar Tractor Co., 1929-31 (Box 6, Folder 149)
        - Farm machinery, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 150)
        - Government publications, 1947, 1951, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 151)
        - Illustrations, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 152)
        - International Harvester Co., 1951-52, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 153)
        - Mechanic's Magazine [photocopy], 1834 Oct 11 (Box 6, Folder 154)
        - Photographs, 1928-32, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 155)
        - Sorting machines, n.d.
      - Draft 1, typescript, carbon, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 156-57)
      - Draft 1, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 158-60)
      - Draft 2, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 161)
      - Draft 4, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 162)
      - Galley setting draft, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 163-65)
      - Post-publication correspondence, 1952-53 (Box 7, Folder 166)
      - Clippings, 1952-53 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - When Lincoln Went to Gettysburg
      - Publishing contract, 1954 May 11 (Box 7, Folder 168)
      - Book review, Goucher Alumnae Quarterly, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 169)
      - Clippings, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 170)
      - Interview confirmation, 1955 May 7 (Box 7, Folder 171)
      - Post-publication correspondence, 1955
  - PROPOSED BOOK PROJECTS
    - Abraham Lincoln and the Mississippi Bridge
      - Outline, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - The Age of Steam
      - Outline, drafts, typescript, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - [ Champlain ]
      - Outline, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - [ Communications ]
      - notes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Earth Shrinkers
      - Outline, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Famous Skyscrapers of the World
      - Outline, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - The First American Flags
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - George Stephenson and the Rocket
      - Outlines, typescript, 1954, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Machine Made
      - Outline, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 180)
      - Publishing contract, 1936 Aug 25
    - Matthew Fontaine Maury
      - Outline, drafts, typescript, carbon, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Operation Big Bounce
      - Outline, drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 182)
      - Research material, Bell Laboratories, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Sails, Rails and Steam Engines
      - Outlines, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - The Second American Revolution
      - Chapter outlines, typescript and holograph, 1962 Jun 21 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - [ Submarines ]
      - Note, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 186)
      - Outline, typescript, n.d.
    - Tell the World
      - Outlines, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - Transportation
      - Outline, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Whirly-birds
      - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 189)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 190)
      - Outline, drafts, typescript, 1957
      - Research material, 1952-57, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 191)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Ideas for books, 1960-65, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - COLUMNS
    "Gold Dust From Gotham," Cripple Creek Gold Rush
    - Column drafts, typescript (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - Published columns, 1952-56, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 194-97)
    - "Post Impressions," Baltimore Daily Gazette
      - Published columns, 1924-26, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 198)
      - Fan mail, 1924, Jan 4
    - St. Nicholas magazine
      - Advertisement
    - Vogue magazine
      See: Personal Papers, Scrapbook 1, Pages 2-3, Box 22, folder 719
  - MOTION PICTURES
    - Delaware
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 199)
      - Outlines, n.d.
      - Statement of theme, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 200)
      - Scripts
        - Draft 1, holograph, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 201)
        - Draft 2, typescript and holograph, 1945 Aug 24
        - Draft 3, typescript, [1945] Aug 29 (Box 8, Folder 202)
        - Shooting typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 203)
        - Miscellaneous script pages, n.d.
    - Fourteen Uncles
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 204)
      - Outlines
        - Draft 1, typescript, carbon, 1939 May 2 (Box 8, Folder 205)
        - Draft 2, typescript, corrected, 1939 May 11
        - Draft 3, typescript, carbon, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 206)
        - Draft 4, typescript, carbon, 1939 May 25
        - Draft 5, typescript, carbon, 1939 May 31 (Box 8, Folder 207)
        - Draft 6, typescript, corrected, 1939
    - Georgia
      - Script, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Melody Makers
      See also: Stage plays, Knights of Song, Box 12, folder 413-15
      - Outline, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Paris-on-the-Seine
      - Outline, drafts with notes, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Pedigreed Pictures
      - Pamphlet, draft, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 211)
      - Collies
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 212)
        - Outline, n.d.
        - Shooting script, typescript corrected, n.d.
      - Greyhounds
        - Outline, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 213)
      - Poodles
        - Outline, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 214)
        - Shooting scripts, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Pennsylvania
      - Background notes (Box 8, Folder 216)
      - Outlines, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 217)
      - Scripts
        - Draft pages, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 218)
        - Draft 1, typescript, corrected, 1945 Sep 25 (Box 8, Folder 219)
        - Draft 2, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Romance of the Reaper
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 221)
      - Program, Centennial of the Reaper, 1931 Dec 2
  - PAGEANTS
    - American Banker's Association
      - Tentative outline, 1960 Sep 8 (Box 8, Folder 222)
      - Program, 1960 Sep 20
    - American Jewish Tercentenary
      Background material
      - Clippings, 1953-55
      - Correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 8, Folder 224)
      - George Washington letter [facsimile], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 225)
      - Program planning booklets, 1953-54 (Box 8, Folder 226)
      - Tercentenary pageant guidelines, drafts, typescript, carbon, 1951-55 (Box 8, Folder 227)
      - Production materials
        - Armbands (Box 9, Folder 228)
        - Clippings, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 229)
        - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 230)
        - "The Fighting Jew" [play], typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 231)
        - Invitations, 1955 May (Box 9, Folder 232)
        - Notes, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 233)
        - Pageant blueprint, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 234)
        - Photograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 235)
        - Press release, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 236)
        - Program, 1955 May 15 (Box 9, Folder 237)
        - Rehearsal schedules, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 238)
        - Stage blueprint, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 239)
        - Technical guidelines, 1955 Apr 28 (Box 9, Folder 240)
        - "Unto This Day" [play], typescript photocopy, corrected, 1955 May 15 (Box 9, Folder 241)
      - Post-production material
        - Clippings, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 242)
        - Correspondence, 1956
    - Declaration of Independence 175th Anniversary
      - Clipping, 1951 Jul 5 (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - Forsythorama
      See also: Scrapbook 2, Oversize, Box 28, folder 859.
      - Clippings, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 244)
      - Contract, 1949 Apr 9 (Box 9, Folder 245)
      - "Lantern in the Pines" [play], typescript pages, photocopy, [1949]
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 246)
      - Photograph, n.d.
      - Programs, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 247)
      - Publicity material, 1949
      - Information on Winston-Salem, North Carolina, n.d.
    - Freedom Bond Drive
      - "The Spectacle of Independence," advertisement, 1950 May 14 (Box 9, Folder 248)
    - Gettysburg Centennial
      - Civil War Times Illustrated, memorial issue, 1963 Nov (Box 9, Folder 249)
      - Clippings, 1962-69 (Box 9, Folder 250)
      - Description of events, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 251)
      - Photographs, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 252)
      - Post-production correspondence, 1963 Jul 25 (Box 9, Folder 253)
      - Program, 1963 Nov (Box 9, Folder 254)
      - Ticket, 1963 Nov 19
    - Great Lakes Exhibition
      - "Parade of the Years" program, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 255)
      - Photograph, n.d.
    - Hallowed Earth Ceremony
      - Tentative outline, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 256)
    - Jewish National Fund Pageant
      - Clippings, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 257)
    - L. Bamberger & Co.
      - Broadcast suggestions, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 258)
      - Christmas programs, 1930 Dec (Box 9, Folder 259)
      - Clippings, 1930-31 (Box 9, Folder 260)
      - Correspondence, 1930 Oct (Box 9, Folder 261)
      - Photographs, 1929, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 262)
      - Press release, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 263)
      - Production notes, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 264)
      - Show outlines, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 265)
      - Show sketches, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration
      - "The Doorway" [play], typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 267)
      - Program, 1944 May 7 (Box 9, Folder 268)
    - Mr. Lincoln Goes to Gettysburg
      - Clippings, 1952-53 (Box 9, Folder 269)
      - Invitation, [1952]
      - Notes, n.d.
      - Photographs, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 270)
      - Postcards, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 271)
      - Post-production correspondence, 1952 Nov 12
      - Schedule, 1952 Oct 18 (Box 9, Folder 272)
    - Niagarama
      - Clippings, 1961, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 273)
        See also: Oversize, Box 27, folder 853
      - Notes, n.d.
      - Magazine article, Holiday
        See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 853
      - Photographs, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 274)
      - Poster
      - Recorded background music [audiodiscs]
    - Paradise Hills
      - Advertisements, 1960, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 275)
      - Clippings, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 276)
      - Invitations, [1960] (Box 9, Folder 277)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 278)
      - Photographs, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 279)
      - Production expenses, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 280)
      - Research correspondence, 1960 Aug 25 (Box 9, Folder 281)
      - Site maps, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 282)
      - Time schedules, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - Rochester Pageant of Progress
      - Clippings, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 284)
      - Production budget notes, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 285)
      - Scrapbook, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 286-89)
    - Sandy Point Project
      - Comprehensive study page, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 290)
    - War Bond Campaign
      See also: Weirton Steel Company, 1944
      - Labor Day Celebration, Box 10, folders 354-56
      - Proposal, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 291)
    - Weirton Steel Company
      - 1942 Labor Day Celebration
        - Actor profiles, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 292)
        - "Attack" [play]
          - Draft 1, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 293)
          - Draft 2, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1942 Aug 31 (Box 10, Folder 294)